College English Test, Band 6,
Part 2, Listening comprehension.
Section A. Directions.
this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear some questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question,
you must choose the best answer from the four choices marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Conversation 1.
I'd like to go to the States, but if I took the job there, I wouldn't get a very
good salary. Really?
I thought salaries were high there, but there would be some fringe benefits,
presumably. Oh yes, it'd be stimulating, and it has some advantages.
What else do you have in mind?
Well, there's a position in Portugal.
How does it compare?
It'd offer greater security because it'd be on a home -based contract.
And salary? Much better.
I'd get an overseas allowance, plus free accommodation from the firm.
Presumably you'd be given moving expenses for the Portugal job?
Yes, but just to complicate matters, there's a possibility of a post in São Paulo.
That's Brazil, isn't it?
Yes, and I'd get a promotion if I took a post there.
I'd love to go to Brazil.
But there are some disadvantages.
I'd have to do a five -year term there.
That's no problem, surely.
Well, not at the moment, but if there were a change in family circumstances, I'd be
a long way from home.
But if you're worried about distance, isn't that the same problem with the States?
Yes, but in the States, I'd be on an annual contract, so I could leave fairly
quickly if I needed to.
And Portugal? Well, that's almost next door, isn't it?
I could visit home every few months if necessary.
I can see you've got a difficult choice to make.
Well, fortunately, I don't have to make up my mind about any of them yet.
In fact, I haven't even been called for an interview.
one to four are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question one. What does the man say about the job in the States?
Question two. What benefit would the man get if he took the post in Sao Paulo?
Question three. What does the man say is the disadvantage of working in Brazil?
Question four. What do we learn from the end of the conversation?
Conversation two. is it, Bob?
You sounded pretty serious on the phone.
Have we still got a budget problem?
I don't know.
I hope not.
The meeting's on Friday.
But that's not what I want to talk to you about.
Close the door, will you?
It's Marcia. Marcia?
What about her?
I'm worried. I don't know what to do.
She's just not performing.
We may have to let her go.
her? She's been with us a long time,
If she leaves, it'll be a big loss to us.
She's done really excellent work.
Yes, but lately, the last month or so, in fact, there have been a of problems.
She's changed. Not only does she have a tendency to be moody all the time, but she
misses appointments, doesn't follow through on projects, and doesn't seem to plan
anything till the last minute.
Did she ever explain why she didn't show up for the Denver trip?
No. She said she was sorry and that it wouldn't happen again.
Something about a mix -up on arrangements to get to the airport.
Now, whenever anybody mentions the subject to her, she just goes silent.
I don't know.
Thank goodness David pulled us out of the hole on that one.
Yes, he did a really fine job filling in for like that at the last minute.
don't think it was the first time he's had to do that.
If we knew all the facts, I think we'd find that he's been covering for Marcia on
quite a few projects.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What did the man do before he came to see the woman?
Question 6. What does the man say about Marcia?
Question 7. How did Marcia explain why she didn't show up for the Denver trip?
Question 8. What does the man say about David?
Question Section B.
Directions. In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear some questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices,
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Passage 1.
Larry arrived early for his speaking engagement.
He positioned the table so that he could move close to the audience at strategic
points in the speech.
He had read that speakers can be more persuasive if they invade the personal space
of listeners, encouraging an emotional response.
For the same reason, he placed the chairs close to each other and raised the
temperature to a slightly uncomfortable level.
The purpose of the speech was to encourage the audience of corporate executives and
local business owners to support local sports groups.
To enhance his credibility with the audience, Larry had brought some slides of his
family attending sports events.
One photo showed him at an awards ceremony where he had been honored for his
financial contribution to a local baseball team.
Realizing that this particular audience would find his regional accent unattractive,
Larry planned to speak with an accent that would be more acceptable to his audience.
After reading a book on how to dress for success, he had purchased an expensive dark
navy suit and golden tie.
He chose colors and styles known to communicate power and influence.
Just before people began entering the hall, Larry dimmed the lights and turned up
the sound system, which was playing soft music, hoping to create a warm personal
atmosphere for the speech.
He hoped that these added effects would encourage his audience to support local
sports teams. He had also planned the content of his speech to focus on the teams
with the best records, the ones that had won the most games in the last season.
Questions 9 to 12 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9. How can a speaker make himself more persuasive when delivering a speech?
Question 10. For what purpose was Larry going to make a speech?
Question 11. Why did Larry purchase an expensive navy suit and golden tie?
Question 12. Why did Larry dim the lights and turn up the sound system before people
entered the Question 13.
Passage 2. Phyllis Wheatley was a young African American slave who belonged to
landowner John Wheatley in colonial America.
She was also a poet and the first African American ever to publish a book.
Her poems on various subjects, religious and moral, was printed in Boston in 1773,
three years before the signing of the Declaration of Independence.
Early slaves were generally denied education, but Wheatley was allowed by her owner
to study poetry, Latin, and the and by the time she reached her late teens she had
written enough poetry to put together a slender book of verse.
Even so, publication was difficult.
The publisher, fearful of being cheated, forced her to submit to a scholarly
examination by a board of educated men, including the colonial governor.
The board of judges questioned Wheatley extensively and ruled that she was educated
enough to have written the book.
Only then was publication permitted.
Wheatley may have been the first, but she was not the only slave to write a during
the growing days of the republic.
Unfortunately, most of the early popular African American writers have been all but
forgotten in modern times, until now.
A Cornell professor, Henry Louis Gates, recently started a research project looking
into 19th century African American fiction and poetry.
In the process, he uncovered numerous lost works, almost half of which were written
by African American women.
In varied literary styles, the newly resurfaced manuscripts offered a rich stock of
African American culture, recreating, among other things, the early days of slavery
and the importance of religion to the slave.
Questions 13 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
13. What does the speaker say about Phyllis Wheatley?
Question 14. What was Wheatley forced to do to get her book published?
Question 15. What did Professor Henry Louis Gates uncover in the process of his
research? Section C.
Directions. this section, you will hear recordings of lectures or talks, followed by
some questions. The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then, mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one, with a single line through
the center. Now, listen to the following recording and answer questions 16 to 19.
Hello, everybody. I am happy to introduce our admirable speaker for today's lecture,
Dr. Brick Blue.
Dr. Blue, Professor of Management at Columbia University, has written numbers of
articles and books on the topic of making holidays more meaningful in recent years,
which is helpful, especially to those who are too busy to make perfect private
plans. Dr. Hello, everyone.
Have you ever thought of making your holidays more meaningful?
Well, here is some advice for you.
It's hard to focus on the true meaning of the holidays when you're rushing from one
shopping mall to the next.
Try this. Six to ten weeks before the holiday season, sketch out a weekly calendar
with all your holiday obligations.
Then, start eliminating.
Weed out and delegate as much as you can.
You'll free up more time for real connecting.
It's better to give than to receive, and that applies to more than material goods.
Some ways to spread cheer to those in need.
your kids deliver homemade holiday cookies to a retirement home.
Schedule a visit to the children's cancer ward at a local hospital to deliver
baskets of toys.
Help serve a holiday meal at a homeless shelter.
How much money does your family spend on meaningless food?
Soft drinks, chips,
cookies, and the like.
Re -examine your food choices and buying patterns and pass the savings on.
Calculate how much you spend on junk food and gift that money to a charity.
Or donate two percent of your food purchases to a food bank.
Rituals anchor holidays and give kids a sense of continuity and a tradition they can
pass on for years to come.
It can be as simple as lighting candles, singing songs, or saying a special prayer.
Other ideas. Take a holiday hike in the woods.
Throw a lake party.
Host an annual holiday dessert potluck.
It's never too early to teach kids to share.
Explain to your children that not all boys and girls have gifts to open on the
holidays, and ask if they'd like to share some of theirs.
Most kids are eager to pick out and wrap old favorites, especially if they're
involved in to the recipients.
toys goes for grown -ups as well.
Old computers, golf clubs, CD players, or cell phones are meaningful holiday
donations. You can't stop holiday commercialism, but you can refuse to partake.
Kill your television and engage kids and family in more festive activities.
Give kids disposable cameras and have an afternoon of photo taking.
Make cookies for an assisted living center.
Head to the local ice rink, museum, or aquarium.
Drag out the markers and paints and make homemade New Year's cards.
Instead of supporting plastics, box stores, and rampant consumerism, make gifts more
meaningful. Buy at small, local stores.
Make your own holiday cards and donate the savings to charity.
As much as you want to connect with your family and friends, it's essential to carve
out time for yourself, even if it's just 10 minutes a day.
Take time for meditation, introspection,
yoga, a solitary hike, gazing at the evening stars.
When days get busy and stressful, schedule an afternoon siesta during which everyone
goes to his or her room for 45 minutes to read, nap, and play quietly.
Lock yourself in the bathroom with a hot bath and don't wait until New Year's Day to
rethink your personal priorities.
List them now and let the magic of the holidays inspire you.
I hope you will enjoy your holidays better after today's talk.
Thank you very much.
Question 16. Who will benefit particularly from Dr.
Blue's books? Question 17.
Which is not mentioned as a way to give kids a sense of continuity and a tradition?
Question 18. How could we make kids more enthusiastic to share with others?
Question 19. What does Dr.
say is essential for holidays?
Now, listen to the following recording and answer questions 20 to 22.
Green is an important color in nature.
It is the color of grass and the leaves on trees.
It is also the color of most growing plants.
Sometimes the word green means young, fresh and growing.
Sometimes it describes something that is not yet ripe or finished.
For example, a greenhorn is someone who has no experience, who is new to a
situation. In the 15th a greenhorn was a young cow or ox whose horns had not yet
developed. A century or so later, a greenhorn was a soldier who had not yet had any
experience in battle.
By the 18th century, a greenhorn had the same meaning it has today, a person who is
new in a job.
Green is also the color used to describe the powerful emotion, jealousy.
The green -eyed monster is not a frightening creature from outer space.
It is an expression used about 400 years ago by British writer William Shakespeare
in his play Othello.
It describes the unpleasant feeling a person has when someone has something he
wants. A young man may suffer from the green -eyed monster if his girlfriend begins
going out with someone else.
Or that green -eyed monster may affect your friend if you get a pay raise and she
does not. In most places in the world, a green light is a sign to move ahead.
A green light on a traffic signal means your car can continue on.
In everyday speech, a green light means approval to continue with the project.
We want you to know we have a green light to continue the series next week.
Question 20. What is this passage mainly about?
Question 21. What does a greenhorn refer to today?
Question 22. When was the expression green -eyed monster first introduced?
Question 23. today?
Now listen to the following recording and answer questions 23 to 25.
The first magazine was a little periodical called The Review and it was started in
London in 1704.
It looked a lot like the newspapers of the time, but in terms of its content, it was
much different. Newspapers were concerned mainly with news events, but The Review
focused on important domestic issues of the day, as well as the policies of the
government. Now in England at the time, people could still be thrown in jail for
publishing articles that were critical of the King, and that's what happened to
Daniel Defoe. He was the outspoken founder of The Review.
Defoe actually wrote the first issue of The Review from prison.
You see, he had been arrested because of his writings that criticized the politics
of the Church of England, which was headed by the King.
After his release, Defoe continued to produce The Review and the magazine started to
appear on a more frequent schedule, about three times a week.
It didn't take long for other magazines to start popping up.
In 1709, a magazine called The Tattler began publication.
This new magazine contained a of news,
poetry, political analysis, and philosophical essays.
According to the speaker, how was The Review different from early newspapers?
Question 24. Why was Daniel Defoe arrested?
Question 25. What does the speaker say about The Tattler?